<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Keys are in Dynamics AX - Tag - Dynamics 365 &amp; Power Platform | nuxulu.com</title>
        <link>https://nuxulu.com/tags/keys-are-in-dynamics-ax/</link>
        <description>Keys are in Dynamics AX - Tag - Dynamics 365 &amp; Power Platform | nuxulu.com</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/tags/keys-are-in-dynamics-ax/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Simple summary Keys are in Dynamics AX</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2017-01-02-simple-summary-keys-are-in-dynamics-ax/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>luan52@outlook.com</author><dc:creator>Max Nguyen</dc:creator><guid>https://nuxulu.com/2017-01-02-simple-summary-keys-are-in-dynamics-ax/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>
<p>There is a maximum of one <code>Primary Key</code> per table, whereas a table can have several <code>alternate keys</code>. The <code>primary key</code> is usually the type of key that other tables, called child tables, refer to when a <code>foreign key</code> field in those other tables need a relational identifier.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For new tables the default is a <code>primary key</code> based on the <code>RecId</code> field , incremented number or a completely meaningless number that is generated by the system <code>surrogate key</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>As <strong>The RecId data type</strong>, <code>surrogate keys</code> exist on a primary key table. As <strong>The RefRecId ETD</strong>, surrogate foreign keys exist on a foreign key table (Ex: <code>Party</code> field is on <code>CustTable</code> Table).</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>Alternate key</code> can be chosen as the <code>Replacement Key</code> of a table that can display on forms instead of a meaningless numeric <code>primary key</code> value. Each table can have a maximum of one <code>replacement key</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><code>Natural key</code> has meaning to people. A set of fields that uniquely identify a record and would have formed the primary key of the table, if not for the existence of a <code>surrogate key</code>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Relations represents a <code>foreign key</code>.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>Thank you for reading!</p>
]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
