<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>error - Tag - Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations | nuxulu.com</title>
        <link>https://nuxulu.com/tags/error/</link>
        <description>error - Tag - Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations | nuxulu.com</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</webMaster><copyright>copyright text</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/tags/error/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>AX1004 error in Dynamics AX</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2017-01-02-ax1004-error/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Max Nguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2017-01-02-ax1004-error/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I got this error at version Dynamics 2012 R3 CU9, SQL Server 2014, Windows Server 2012 R2.</p>
<p>Those kind of errors will come when you move report from Dev Server to Live Server, even compilation in <em>DP Class, Query, Contract, table</em> … without any error</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/imagesposts/AX1004-error.png" title="Image" data-thumbnail="/imagesposts/AX1004-error.png" data-sub-html="<h2>Image_rounded</h2><p>Image</p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Image_rounded</figcaption>
    </figure>{:.rounded}</p>
<p><span style="color: red">AX1004: Reference System.Core, Version=4.0.0.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=b77a5c561934e089 was not a valid model assembly.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: red">MSB3644: The reference assemblies for framework “.NETFramework,Version=v4.0” were not found. To resolve this, install the SDK or Targeting Pack for this framework version or retarget your application to a version of the framework for which you have the SDK </span></p>
<h3 id="cause">Cause</h3>
<p>There is no reference Assemblies Version 4.0  under <code>C:\Program Files (x86)\Reference Assemblies\Microsoft\Framework\.NETFramework</code> on Windows Server 2012 R2 (only Version 4.5 it have)</p>
<h3 id="solution">Solution</h3>
<p>Copy those Assemblies from your any where (Windows 7,8,10) to Server</p>
<p>Restore and compile again.</p>
<p>Thank you for reading!</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Only integrated security is supported for AX queries</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2016-01-15-only-integrated-security-is-supported-for-ax-queries/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 16:22:50 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Max Nguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2016-01-15-only-integrated-security-is-supported-for-ax-queries/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>I updated my dynamics Ax development Environment by restoring Database from <strong>Production Database</strong> . After the restoring the database, when I run any report form Dynamics Ax, all gave error  <code>“Only integrated security is supported for AX queries.”</code>
The reporting Services are still working fine.
For this, best way to redeploy them, create a new report folder, open Microsoft Dynamics Ax 2012 Management Shell (make sure you run Powershell as Administrator).</p>
<p><code>Publish-AXReport -ReportName *</code></p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>SSRS Report Server Settings Validation Error- AX 2012 R3 CU9</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2016-01-15-ssrs-report-server-settings-validation-error-ax-2012-r3-cu9/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 16:22:50 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Max Nguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2016-01-15-ssrs-report-server-settings-validation-error-ax-2012-r3-cu9/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Recently I updated my dynamics Ax development Environment by restoring Database from Production Dynamics AX DB and I got this problem</p>
<p><strong>Make sure that SQL Server Reporting Services is configured correctly. Verify the Web Service URL and Report Manager URL configuration in the SQL Reporting Services Configuration Manager.</strong></p>
<p>Anyway, The reporting Services are still working fine and i have already granted the AX Admin as System Administrator under site settings, Home folder settings and DynamicsAX folder with <code>“Browser, Content Manager, DynamicsAXBrowser, My Reports, Publisher, Report Builder”</code> roles.</p>
<p>Solution is we need disable UAC (I&rsquo;m using Windows Server 2012 R2) by <em>Regedit</em></p>
<p>go to Regedit: <code>“HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINESOFTWAREMicrosoftWindowsCurrentVersionpoliciessystem”</code> and changing the DWORD <code>“EnableLUA”</code> from 1 to 0.</p>
<p>After the reboot, UAC is disabled.</p>
<p>Happy AXsing</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>AX 2012 R3 CU8 CU9 and TFS Online 2013 Error</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2015-11-20-ax-2012-r3-cu8-cu9-and-tfs-online-2013-error/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 13:52:40 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Max Nguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2015-11-20-ax-2012-r3-cu8-cu9-and-tfs-online-2013-error/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>When you try connecting between TFS and Dynamics AX CU8, CU9 and you got error like this:</p>
<p><em>Error 1</em>
Team Foundation services are not available from server  <strong>****.visualstudio.com/defaultcollection.</strong></p>
<p>Technical information (for administrator):</p>
<p><code>TF400813: Resource not available for anonymous access. Client authentication required.</code></p>
<p><em>Error 2</em></p>
<p><em>Could not load file or assembly &lsquo;Microsoft.TeamFoundation.Client, Version=10.0.0.0, Culture=neutral, PublicKeyToken=b03f5f7f11d50a3a&rsquo; or one of its dependencies. The system cannot find the file specified.</em></p>
<p>Client computers that are not running Visual Studio 2010 must have the <a href="https://visualstudiogallery.msdn.microsoft.com/a37e19fb-3052-4fc9-bef7-4a4682069a75" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">Team Foundation Server 2010 SP1 Object Model</a> installed to use TFS source control with Microsoft Dynamics AX.</p>
<p>TFS support TFS 2010, TFS 2012, TFS 2013 and TFS online, but to connect to these from AX you will need “TFS 2010 object model Sp1” which is client to connect to server.</p>
<p>After install Team Foundation Server 2010 SP1 Object Model above. Client computers that are not running Visual Studio 2010 must have hotfix KB <a href="http://support.microsoft.com/kb/2662296" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">2662296</a> installed to use TFS source control with Microsoft Dynamics AX.
Once you have installed the above , restart your AOS and open AX client again, then try to check-in some Jobs.</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Web Services on IIS - Exception has been thrown by the target of an invocation</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2015-08-04-web-services-on-iis-exception-has-been-thrown-by-the-target-of-an-invocation-ax-installation/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Max Nguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2015-08-04-web-services-on-iis-exception-has-been-thrown-by-the-target-of-an-invocation-ax-installation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>When I try to install Web Services on IIS for Retails POS Component, and I got the problem.</p>
<p>This scenario shouldn&rsquo;t be common in a production environment, but, it is indeed quite common in a VM machine (I&rsquo;m using virtual machine Hyper-V on Windows 8.1)</p>
<p></p>
<p><span style="color: red">Error:</span></p>
<p></p>
<p><code>Exception has been thrown by the target of an invocation</code></p>
<p></p>
<p>So, the problem is relate to thee AOS Service account, which by default is usually <code>NT AUTHORITYNETWORK SERVICE</code> account.</p>
<p></p>
<p>but because of we are running on a Domain Controller Server, we should use any specific Domain account created just for running AOS services, then you’ll success installing Web Services on IIS.</p>
<p></p>
<p>Now please restart services and try again.</p>
<p>Thank you for reading</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
