<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>manufacturing - Tag - Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations | nuxulu.com</title>
        <link>https://nuxulu.com/tags/manufacturing/</link>
        <description>manufacturing - Tag - Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations | nuxulu.com</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</webMaster><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/tags/manufacturing/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Shaper</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/news/shaper/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>luan52@outlook.com</author><dc:creator>Max Nguyen</dc:creator><guid>https://nuxulu.com/news/shaper/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Drawing is a form of visual art in which a person uses various drawing instruments to mark paper or another two-dimensional medium. Instruments include graphite pencils, pen and ink, various kinds of paints, inked brushes, colored pencils, crayons, charcoal, chalk, pastels, various kinds of erasers, markers, styluses, and various metals (such as silverpoint). Digital drawing is the act of using a computer to draw. Common methods of digital drawing include a stylus or finger on a touchscreen device, stylus- or finger-to-touchpad, or in some cases, a mouse. There are many digital art programs and devices.</p>
<p>A drawing instrument releases a small amount of material onto a surface, leaving a visible mark. The most common support for drawing is paper, although other materials, such as cardboard, wood, plastic, leather, canvas, and board, may be used. Temporary drawings may be made on a blackboard or whiteboard or indeed almost anything. The medium has been a popular and fundamental means of public expression throughout human history. It is one of the simplest and most efficient means of communicating visual ideas. The wide availability of drawing instruments makes drawing one of the most common artistic activities.</p>
<p>In addition to its more artistic forms, drawing is frequently used in commercial illustration, animation, architecture, engineering and technical drawing. A quick, freehand drawing, usually not intended as a finished work, is sometimes called a sketch. An artist who practices or works in technical drawing may be called a drafter, draftsman or a draughtsman.</p>
<p>Drawing is one of the oldest forms of human expression within the visual arts. It is generally concerned with the marking of lines and areas of tone onto paper/other material, where the accurate representation of the visual world is expressed upon a plane surface. Traditional drawings were monochrome, or at least had little colour, while modern colored-pencil drawings may approach or cross a boundary between drawing and painting. In Western terminology, drawing is distinct from painting, even though similar media often are employed in both tasks. Dry media, normally associated with drawing, such as chalk, may be used in pastel paintings. Drawing may be done with a liquid medium, applied with brushes or pens. Similar supports likewise can serve both: painting generally involves the application of liquid paint onto prepared canvas or panels, but sometimes an underdrawing is drawn first on that same support.</p>
<p>Drawing is often exploratory, with considerable emphasis on observation, problem-solving and composition. Drawing is also regularly used in preparation for a painting, further obfuscating their distinction. Drawings created for these purposes are called studies.</p>
<p>There are several categories of drawing, including figure drawing, cartooning, doodling, and freehand. There are also many drawing methods, such as line drawing, stippling, shading, the surrealist method of entopic graphomania (in which dots are made at the sites of impurities in a blank sheet of paper, and lines are then made between the dots), and tracing (drawing on a translucent paper, such as tracing paper, around the outline of preexisting shapes that show through the paper).</p>
<p>A quick, unrefined drawing may be called a sketch.</p>
<p>In fields outside art, technical drawings or plans of buildings, machinery, circuitry and other things are often called &ldquo;drawings&rdquo; even when they have been transferred to another medium by printing.</p>
<p>Content from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Drawing" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wikipedia</a>.</p>
]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Square License</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/news/square-license/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate><author>luan52@outlook.com</author><dc:creator>Max Nguyen</dc:creator><guid>https://nuxulu.com/news/square-license/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>A license (American English) or licence (British English) is an official permission or permit to do, use, or own something (as well as the document of that permission or permit).</p>
<p>A license can be granted by a party to another party as an element of an agreement between those parties. A shorthand definition of a license is &ldquo;an authorization to use licensed material.&rdquo;</p>
<p>In particular, a license may be issued by authorities, to allow an activity that would otherwise be forbidden. It may require paying a fee or proving a capability. The requirement may also serve to keep the authorities informed on a type of activity, and to give them the opportunity to set conditions and limitations.</p>
<p>A licensor may grant a license under intellectual property laws to authorize a use (such as copying software or using a (patented) invention) to a licensee, sparing the licensee from a claim of infringement brought by the licensor. A license under intellectual property commonly has several components beyond the grant itself, including a term, territory, renewal provisions, and other limitations deemed vital to the licensor.</p>
<p>Term: many licenses are valid for a particular length of time. This protects the licensor should the value of the license increase, or market conditions change. It also preserves enforceability by ensuring that no license extends beyond the term of the agreement.</p>
<p>Territory: a license may stipulate what territory the rights pertain to. For example, a license with a territory limited to &ldquo;North America&rdquo; (Mexico/United States/Canada) would not permit a licensee any protection from actions for use in Japan.</p>
<p>A shorthand definition of license is &ldquo;a promise by the licensor not to sue the licensee&rdquo;. That means without a license any use or exploitation of intellectual property by a third party would amount to copying or infringement. Such copying would be improper and could, by using the legal system, be stopped if the intellectual property owner wanted to do so.</p>
<p>Intellectual property licensing plays a major role in business, academia and broadcasting. Business practices such as franchising, technology transfer, publication and character merchandising entirely depend on the licensing of intellectual property. Land licensing (proprietary licensing) and IP licensing form sub-branches of law born out of the interplay of general laws of contract and specific principles and statutory laws relating to these respective assets.</p>
<p>Content from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/License" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">wikipedia</a>.</p>
]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
