<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>services on Dynamics 365 Finance Operations &amp; Power Platform</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/categories/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in services on Dynamics 365 Finance Operations &amp; Power Platform</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://nuxulu.com/47</url>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/47</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 18:47:00 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/categories/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Types of services in Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012</title>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2016-11-10-types-services-microsoft-dynamics-ax-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 18:47:00 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2016-11-10-types-services-microsoft-dynamics-ax-2012/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;document-services&#34;&gt;Document services&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Document services use documents to represent business objects such as purchase and sales orders, customers, vendors, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A document service is composed of the following components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document query&lt;/strong&gt; : This is a query that is created in the &lt;strong&gt;Application Object Tree (AOT)&lt;/strong&gt; and contains all the tables that are related to the business object that you want to expose. Based on this query, the Document Service Generation Wizard can be used to generate the other artifacts that make up the document service.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table AxBC classes&lt;/strong&gt; : An &lt;code&gt;AxBC&lt;/code&gt; class is a wrapper for a table and contains business logic that is needed for &lt;strong&gt;Create, Read, Update, Delete (CRUD)&lt;/strong&gt; operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document class&lt;/strong&gt; : The purpose of the document class is to contain business logic that is associated with the creation and modification of the business entity itself. For example, the &lt;code&gt;AxdCustomer&lt;/code&gt; class could contain logic to handle party information of a customer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Document service class&lt;/strong&gt; : This is the actual service implementation class and extends the &lt;code&gt;AifDocumentService&lt;/code&gt; class. This class implements the service operations that are published through the service contract.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When creating document services, developers need to make sure &lt;strong&gt;that the business object is mapped correctly to the document query&lt;/strong&gt;. The document services framework will handle all other things such as the serialization and deserialization of XML, date effectiveness, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Document services can be deployed using the integration ports and all available adapters can be used.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only integrated security is supported for AX queries</title>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2016-01-15-only-integrated-security-is-supported-for-ax-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 16:22:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2016-01-15-only-integrated-security-is-supported-for-ax-queries/</guid>
      <description>I updated my dynamics Ax development Environment by restoring Database from Production Database . After the restoring the database, when I run any report form Dynamics Ax, all gave error “Only integrated security is supported for AX queries.”
The reporting Services are still working fine.
For this, best way to redeploy them, create a new report folder, open Microsoft Dynamics Ax 2012 Management Shell (make sure you run Powershell as Administrator).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSRS Report Server Settings Validation Error- AX 2012 R3 CU9</title>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2016-01-15-ssrs-report-server-settings-validation-error-ax-2012-r3-cu9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 16:22:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2016-01-15-ssrs-report-server-settings-validation-error-ax-2012-r3-cu9/</guid>
      <description>Recently I updated my dynamics Ax development Environment by restoring Database from Production Dynamics AX DB and I got this problem
Make sure that SQL Server Reporting Services is configured correctly. Verify the Web Service URL and Report Manager URL configuration in the SQL Reporting Services Configuration Manager.
Anyway, The reporting Services are still working fine and i have already granted the AX Admin as System Administrator under site settings, Home folder settings and DynamicsAX folder with “Browser, Content Manager, DynamicsAXBrowser, My Reports, Publisher, Report Builder” roles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
