<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ALM on Dynamics 365 Finance Operations &amp; Power Platform</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/tags/alm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ALM on Dynamics 365 Finance Operations &amp; Power Platform</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://nuxulu.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/tags/alm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>All about Odata actions in Dynamics 365 Finance And Operations</title>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2021-05-25-all-about-odata-actions-in-dynamics-365-finance-and-operations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2021-05-25-all-about-odata-actions-in-dynamics-365-finance-and-operations/</guid>
      <description>Sample article showcasing basic Markdown syntax and formatting for HTML elements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure DevTest Labs powered builds for Dynamics 365 FinOps</title>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2021-05-03-azure-devtest-labs-powered-builds-for-dynamics-365-finops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2021-05-03-azure-devtest-labs-powered-builds-for-dynamics-365-finops/</guid>
      <description>This post has been written thanks to Joris de Gruyter‘s session in the past DynamicsCon: Azure Devops Automation for Finance and Operations Like You’ve Never Seen! And there’s also been some investigation and (a lot of) trial-and-error from my side until everything has been working.
Configuring the build VM in Azure DevTest Labs
If you want to know more about builds, releases, and the Dev ALM of Dynamics 365 you can read my full guide on MSDyn365 &amp;amp; Azure DevOps ALM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Develop custom Data Entities for Dual-write</title>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2021-05-02-develop-custom-data-entities-for-dual-write/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2021-05-02-develop-custom-data-entities-for-dual-write/</guid>
      <description>Dual-write has been around for almost two years now. It’s one of the ways of integrating Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations and Dataverse along with Virtual Entities.
The standard solution comes with many out-of-the-box entities available to synchronize. This has been one of the great improvements since Dual-write was made available in preview, when Juanan and I demoed it in the 2019 Dynamics Saturday in Madrid.
This is how Dual write really works</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamics 365 for Finance &amp; Operations and Azure DevOps</title>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2021-05-01-dynamics-365-for-finance-operations-and-azure-devops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2021-05-01-dynamics-365-for-finance-operations-and-azure-devops/</guid>
      <description>Dynamics 365 for Finance &amp;amp; Operations and Azure DevOps 0.1.1. Azure DevOps Azure DevOps will be the service we will use for source control. Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations supports TFVC out of the box as its version-control system.
But Azure DevOps does not only offer a source control tool. Of course, developers will be the most benefited of using it, but from project management to the functional team and customers, everybody can be involved in using Azure DevOps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LCS API Database Movement with Power Automate</title>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2021-05-05-lcs-api-database-movement-with-powerautomate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2021-05-05-lcs-api-database-movement-with-powerautomate/</guid>
      <description>Hello Dynamics &amp;amp; Power Community,
I’m very happy to announce a good news for you the Dynamics365 F&amp;amp;O Community. I’ve got a little gift for you, as part of the new LCS API.
If you were, like me as an AX 2012 or F&amp;amp;O Technical/Architect Consultant, you probably already suffered from not being able to offer customers the ability to automatically refresh your database from one environment to other. Of course, you could do it via scripts, powershell (but really complicated for LCS and F&amp;amp;O : see even impossible), but finally doing it by code actually….</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
