<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>SSRS - Category - Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations | nuxulu.com</title>
        <link>https://nuxulu.com/categories/ssrs/</link>
        <description>SSRS - Category - Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations | nuxulu.com</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 09:11:11 &#43;0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/categories/ssrs/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Step by Step How to build SSRS Report - Advanced RDP Class</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2016-11-23-step-by-step-how-to-build-ssrs-report---advanced-rdp-class/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 09:11:11 &#43;0900</pubDate>
    <author>Max Nguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2016-11-23-step-by-step-how-to-build-ssrs-report---advanced-rdp-class/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>SSRS Report Server Settings Validation Error- AX 2012 R3 CU9</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2016-01-15-ssrs-report-server-settings-validation-error-ax-2012-r3-cu9/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 16:22:50 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Max Nguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2016-01-15-ssrs-report-server-settings-validation-error-ax-2012-r3-cu9/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<p>Recently I updated my dynamics Ax development Environment by restoring Database from Production Dynamics AX DB and I got this problem</p>
<p><strong>Make sure that SQL Server Reporting Services is configured correctly. Verify the Web Service URL and Report Manager URL configuration in the SQL Reporting Services Configuration Manager.</strong></p>
<p>Anyway, The reporting Services are still working fine and i have already granted the AX Admin as System Administrator under site settings, Home folder settings and DynamicsAX folder with <code>“Browser, Content Manager, DynamicsAXBrowser, My Reports, Publisher, Report Builder”</code> roles.</p>
<p>Solution is we need disable UAC (I&rsquo;m using Windows Server 2012 R2) by <em>Regedit</em></p>
<p>go to Regedit: <code>“HKEY_LOCAL_MACHINESOFTWAREMicrosoftWindowsCurrentVersionpoliciessystem”</code> and changing the DWORD <code>“EnableLUA”</code> from 1 to 0.</p>
<p>After the reboot, UAC is disabled.</p>
<p>Happy AXsing</p>
]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>How to install two instances SSRS on one server</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2015-12-16-how-to-install-2-instances-ssrs-on-1-server/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 09:01:11 &#43;0700</pubDate>
    <author>Max Nguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2015-12-16-how-to-install-2-instances-ssrs-on-1-server/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="scenario">Scenario:</h2>
<p>I have 2 AOS AX (maybe same in one server or different servers), but only one server for reporting server (I will install and configure multiple SRS instances in this server). Thing is how can we install and configure 2 SSRS instances on same server and running for 2 AOS.</p>
<p>easierly, please take a look the picture below</p>
<p></p>
<p><em><strong>Figure 1</strong>: Two SSRS instance are running same server.</em></p>
<h2 id="problems">Problems:</h2>
<p>First you need to install 2 SSRS instance in same server, and install <code>reporting service component</code> for first AOS, this step is very simple. The problems come when we install second <code>reporting service component</code> for second AOS.</p>
<p>Reporting service component uses <strong>business connector</strong> to connect to AX, and it&rsquo;s saved on configuration in Registry. When we install second <code>reporting service component</code> it will through message that component already installed.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-do">How to do:</h2>
<ol>
<li>After installed second instance into <code>C:\Program Files\Microsoft SQL Server\MSRS12.InstanceName\Reporting Services\ReportServer\bin</code>, we need to create one <code>Dynamics.AX.ReportConfiguration.axc</code> file by <strong>AX configuration client</strong> with second AOS information.</li>
</ol>
<p></p>
<ol start="2">
<li>open <code>MS Dyanmics AX Management Shell</code>, run command below:</li>
</ol>
<p><code>Install-AXReportInstanceExtensions –ReportServerInstanceName [SSRSInstanceName] -Credential [DomainNameUserName]</code></p>
<p></p>
<ol start="3">
<li>goto <code>C:\Program Files\Microsoft SQL Server\MSRS12.SecondInstance\Reporting Services\ReportServer</code> fix <code>fileconfi</code> with value from <code>Execution</code> to <code>FullTrust</code></li>
</ol>
<p></p>
<p>After this, remember restart reporting services.</p>
<p></p>
<p>From now on, you can run 2 AX reporting instance in same server.</p>
<p>Thank you for reading!</p>]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
