<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>OneBox - Tag - Dynamics 365 &amp; Power Platform | NUXULU</title>
        <link>https://nuxulu.com/tags/onebox/</link>
        <description>OneBox - Tag - Dynamics 365 &amp; Power Platform | NUXULU</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/tags/onebox/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Getting onebox VHD Dynamics 365 finance and operations virtual machine</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2020-04-06-getting-onebox-vhd-dynamics-365-finance-and-operations-virtual-machine/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>maxnguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2020-04-06-getting-onebox-vhd-dynamics-365-finance-and-operations-virtual-machine/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1. Download Dynamics 365 finance and operations VHD files   Go to the LCS main page and select Shared asset library or go to Shared Asset Library.
  Select the asset type Downloadable VHD.
  Find the VHD you are looking for based on the desired Finance and Operation version. The VHD is divided into multiple file parts that you need to download. For example, the asset files that start with &ldquo;VHD - 10.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Azure Storage Emulator &#39;Port conflict with existing application&#39;, Dynamics 365 finance and operations</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2020-04-05-azure-storage-emulator-port-conflict-with-existing-application/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>maxnguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2020-04-05-azure-storage-emulator-port-conflict-with-existing-application/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The Microsoft Azure storage emulator is a tool that emulates the Azure Blob, Queue, and Table services for local development purposes. You can test your application against the storage services locally without creating an Azure subscription or incurring any costs. When you&rsquo;re satisfied with how your application is working in the emulator, switch to using an Azure storage account in the cloud.
In Dynamics 365 finance and operations onebox environment, we also use Microsoft Azure Storage Emulator for same purposes.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
