<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Exception Handling on Dynamics 365 Finance Operations &amp; Power Platform</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/tags/exception-handling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Exception Handling on Dynamics 365 Finance Operations &amp; Power Platform</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://nuxulu.com/47</url>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/47</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/tags/exception-handling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exception Handling in Dynamics 365 For Finance and Operation</title>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2017-08-07-exception-handling-in-dynamics-365-for-finance-and-operation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2017-08-07-exception-handling-in-dynamics-365-for-finance-and-operation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When we write a code, or make a customization to Dynamics 365 For Operation which is using X++ should make use of Exception Handling to provide some context for the message or a different more useful message. In this article, I will be exploring how I can come up with a uniform way to catch multiple types of exception that can be raised in X++.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-exception-type&#34;&gt;1. Exception type&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many several types of exception and the type differs depending on what caused the error. Much of exception types are determined by the kernel and are not normally thrown by application code. All &lt;strong&gt;exception types&lt;/strong&gt;, however, can be caught, and it is the developers’ responsibility to decide which exceptions need to be handled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exception type is identified using the system-based enumeration called an exception. Because it is a system Enum, it cannot be modified, so users cannot add new exception types.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following table shows the exception literals that are the values of the Exception enumeration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
