<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Questionaire - Tag - Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations | nuxulu.com</title><link>https://dynamics365.github.io/tags/questionaire/</link><description>Questionaire - Tag - Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations | nuxulu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</managingEditor><webMaster>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dynamics365.github.io/tags/questionaire/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dynamics 365 Finance Operations upgrade questionaire</title><link>https://dynamics365.github.io/2020-01-01-ax-upgrade-assessment-clarification-questions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Max Nguyen</author><guid>https://dynamics365.github.io/2020-01-01-ax-upgrade-assessment-clarification-questions/</guid><description><![CDATA[<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>#</th>
<th>Area</th>
<th>Question</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td>Organization Structure</td>
<td>Explain the Organization structure and hierarchy - how many legal entities/companies are involved in the AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version) implementation and how the org structure has been configured in AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>2</td>
<td>Implemented Business Processes in AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version)</td>
<td>What does AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version)(or Current Implemented AX Version) do currently ? What is the main purpose of the current system for example for the supply chain management, only for material planning etc.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>3</td>
<td>Business Criticality</td>
<td>Who or How does the current system impact business ? <br/>What are the business critical operations AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version) currently running? <br/>What is the primary reason to upgrade to AX 2012(or Target AX Version) now?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>4</td>
<td>Modules</td>
<td>Is AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version) Retail and POS/MPOS currently used?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>5</td>
<td>Modules</td>
<td>Is Enterprise Portal functionalities in AX deployed?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>6</td>
<td>Modules</td>
<td>The number of modules used in the current system and list down the same</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>7</td>
<td>Modules</td>
<td>Which of the implemented modules has undergone major changes ?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>8</td>
<td>Customizations Done in AX</td>
<td>Is there any specific customizations for your business done  in the current system. List out the major customizations done</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>9</td>
<td>Coding &amp; any other standards</td>
<td>Is there any specific coding standards following in the current system</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>10</td>
<td>Data Migration</td>
<td>What are the key data maintained in current system ? What are the critical transactional information available? Do you want to migrate all the transactions into AX 2012(or Target AX Version)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>11</td>
<td>Integration Information</td>
<td>What information flow into AX from other systems and does AX provide information to other systems in your environment? Which systems are dependent on AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version) for their operations.<br/>Please provide a list of the integrating systems along with data being exchanged between AX and the other system</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>12</td>
<td>Reports</td>
<td>What are the reports which you use most frequently from AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version)? Provide a list of Custom Reports which were developed for Customer needs in AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>13</td>
<td>Deployment information</td>
<td>Are there region specific localizations deployed?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>14</td>
<td>Deployment information</td>
<td>Are there remote users connecting to the central / distributed access point. Kindly indicate technologies used for remote connectivity</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>15</td>
<td>Deployment information</td>
<td>Information about the license, security roles and configuration keys used during the implementation</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>16</td>
<td>Deployment information</td>
<td>Is this a single site implementation or multi-site. Please provide with a detailed deployment document indicating geographies and technologies used.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>17</td>
<td>Deployment information</td>
<td>What is the current volume of the Production database (in GB) ?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>18</td>
<td>Deployment information</td>
<td>What platform does it run on? Database/OS used? Is it hosted in data center or is it on premise</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>19</td>
<td>Documents</td>
<td>Can you  provide us with Documentation on the implemented system like - Functional Requirement Document (FRD) or the Business Process Analysis (BPA) document and Data Flow Diagram Document (DFD) that was prepared during the implementation</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>20</td>
<td>Documents</td>
<td>Can you provide us with the Solution Design Document &amp; Technical Design Document for the customizations that are deployed in the current AX environment</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>21</td>
<td>ISV / Add On Solutions</td>
<td>If the requirement is to upgrade to AX 2012(or Target AX Version), will Customer liaison with ISV &amp; Third Party Add On Solution providers for compatibility with AX 2012(or Target AX Version) and support issues ?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>22</td>
<td>ISV / Add On Solutions</td>
<td>Please provide us with the documentation on ISV / Add On Solution like its functionality, data touch points with AX, integration method with AX.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>23</td>
<td>ISV / Add On Solutions</td>
<td>What are the ISV / AX Add-on Solutions used . Kindly confirm.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>24</td>
<td>IT Staff</td>
<td>Define the roles and responsibilities of the staff involved in maintaining  the current application? E.g. ERP Manager, System Admin etc.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>25</td>
<td>Testing</td>
<td>Are Test Cases used for Testing the AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version) system available with you?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>26</td>
<td>User and User Roles</td>
<td>Who are the targeted users for the current system like only finance department, only supply chain users accountants etc.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>27</td>
<td>User and User Roles</td>
<td>What are the total number of named and concurrent users on AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version)? What is the peak load of concurrent users</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>28</td>
<td>Support</td>
<td>Are you on an Active Support Plan for AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version) with Microsoft? Do you have an AX 2012(or Target AX Version) license or plan to upgrade in future?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>29</td>
<td>Localization</td>
<td>Is the  GLS Layer implemented for you in AX 2009(or Current Implemented AX Version)?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>30</td>
<td>Partner</td>
<td>Is an AX Partner locally providing you day to day operations support ? Do you intend to use the same partner after AX 2012(or Target AX Version) upgrade?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>31</td>
<td>Cloud Usage</td>
<td>Do you use Cloud Infrastructure for any of your IT systems?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>32</td>
<td>Cloud Usage</td>
<td>Do you use Microsoft Azure for any application?</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>33</td>
<td>Cloud Usage</td>
<td>Do intend to use AX with Azure?</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><strong>List customizations</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Functional Area</th>
<th>Description of Customization</th>
<th>How is this Customization useful to business</th>
<th>Additional Comments</th>
</tr>
</thead>
</table>
<p><strong>List integration</strong></p>
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>#</th>
<th>Integration Description</th>
<th>External System</th>
<th>Type</th>
<th>Direction</th>
<th>AX Module/ Table updated by this integration</th>
<th>Why is this integration useful to business?</th>
<th>Additional Comments from Customer</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>1</td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>