<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Power Automate - Tag - Dynamics 365 &amp; Power Platform | NUXULU</title>
        <link>https://nuxulu.com/tags/power-automate/</link>
        <description>Power Automate - Tag - Dynamics 365 &amp; Power Platform | NUXULU</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/tags/power-automate/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>All about Odata actions in Dynamics 365 Finance And Operations</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2021-05-25-all-about-odata-actions-in-dynamics-365-finance-and-operations/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>maxnguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2021-05-25-all-about-odata-actions-in-dynamics-365-finance-and-operations/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ODATA actions in Data Entities provide a way to inject behaviors into the data model, or expose custom business logic from Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations. You can add actions by adding a method to the data entity and then decorating the method with specific attributes [SysODataActionAttribute]
I use this Odata actions mostly in automation job like after refreshing data from PROD to UAT, we need to enable users, assign company to users, enable batches &hellip; Or simply consume it in Power Automate.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Dynamics 365 FinOps Data Integration using Microsoft Forms (Part 2)</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2020-06-28-dynamics-365-finops-data-integration-using-microsoft-forms-part-2/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Kome Hoang</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2020-06-28-dynamics-365-finops-data-integration-using-microsoft-forms-part-2/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Example two: A new Forms response is submitted then Flow promts for an approval request before a new record is created in Vendors tableIn the last example, we created a simple Flow to create a new Vendor Account from submitted Forms responses. The process was made as simple as it could be: When a new Forms response if submitted, a new Vendor Account will be created on D365FO client.
To make the process more reliable, we will now add an approval step to the Flow.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Dynamics 365 FinOps Data Integration using Microsoft Forms (Part 1)</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2020-05-24-dynamics-365-finops-data-integration-using-microsoft-forms-part-1/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Kome Hoang</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2020-05-24-dynamics-365-finops-data-integration-using-microsoft-forms-part-1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[With any D365FO users, Data Management workspace and Data Entities should have become one of the most used and well-known tools in the system. We all agree how powerful such integration framework is, especially when it comes to a large number of records that we would need to import into different tables.
The classic method that we have been utilizing is to include all source data in a single (or multiple, much depending on the purpose and order of data integration) Excel sheet, trigger an import execution, pass any validation layers that present and ultimately have the data available on D365FO.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
