<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>delete acitons - Tag - Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations | nuxulu.com</title><link>https://dynamics365.github.io/tags/delete-acitons/</link><description>delete acitons - Tag - Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations | nuxulu.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</managingEditor><webMaster>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dynamics365.github.io/tags/delete-acitons/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Overview delete action in Dyanmics AX 2012</title><link>https://dynamics365.github.io/2017-01-19-overview-delete-action-in-dyanmics-ax-2012/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Max Nguyen</author><guid>https://dynamics365.github.io/2017-01-19-overview-delete-action-in-dyanmics-ax-2012/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>We normally create action delete in foreign table to make sure referential integrity in Logic and validation.</p>
<p>The delete action has the following options: <strong>None, Restricted, Cascade, Cascade + Restricted</strong></p>
<h4 id="1-none">1. None:</h4>
<p>This has no effect, and effectively disables the delete action. This is useful if you want to specifically state <em>do nothing</em> so that someone else doesn&rsquo;t try to correct what seems to be an omission.</p>
<h4 id="2-restricted">2. Restricted:</h4>
<p>This will prevent the record from being deleted if there are records in the related table that match the selected relation. This occurs within the <code>validateDelete</code> table event, which is called by the delete table event.</p>
<h4 id="3-cascade">3. Cascade:</h4>
<p>This will delete the record in the related table, based on the relation. Ex: A sales order line is of no use without a sales order. This is an extension of the delete table event.</p>
<h4 id="4-cascade--restricted">4. Cascade + Restricted</h4>
<p>This is a little special. In a two-table scenario, it is the same as <em>Restricted</em>. It will stop the record from being deleted if a related record exists. But if the record is being deleted as part of a cascade from a table related to it, the records will be deleted.</p>
<p>for more infomation about how to create <code>DeleteActions</code> at <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/enus/library/bb315018.aspx" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer ">MSDN</a>.</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>