<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Upgrade - Category - Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations | nuxulu.com</title>
        <link>https://nuxulu.com/categories/upgrade/</link>
        <description>Upgrade - Category - Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations | nuxulu.com</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>luan52@outlook.com (Max Nguyen)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/categories/upgrade/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 Update Process</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2020-01-01-microsoft-dynamics-ax-2012-update-process/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Max Nguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2020-01-01-microsoft-dynamics-ax-2012-update-process/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<h2 id="what-is-an-update">What is an Update?</h2>
<p>Updates include hotfixes, cumulative updates, and feature packs.</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Hotfix</strong>: A fix or set of fixes that address a specific issue, problem, or customer scenario.</li>
<li><strong>Cumulative update</strong>: An update that contains all previous hotfixes to date.</li>
<li><strong>Feature pack</strong>: A group of updates that relate to a feature area or group of functionality. Contains design changes.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="1-types-of-hotfixes">1. Types of Hotfixes</h3>
<p>To determine which type of update is in a package, download the package, and then extract contents and review
them to determine which type of update it is.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/2020-01-01-microsoft-dynamics-ax-2012-update-process/Types-of-Hotfixes.png" title="Image" data-thumbnail="/2020-01-01-microsoft-dynamics-ax-2012-update-process/Types-of-Hotfixes.png" data-sub-html="<h2>Types of Hotfixes</h2><p>Image</p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Types of Hotfixes</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<h3 id="2-how-can-i-tell-if-a-binary-update-requires-a-schema-update-and-model-store-reinitialization">2. How can I tell if a binary update requires a schema update, and model store reinitialization?</h3>
<p>The KB article will indicate  that a hotfix requires a schema update, and that you should reinitialize the model store.
You should assume that all cumulative updates require a schema update, and reinitialize the model store.</p>
<h3 id="3-how-can-i-tell-if-an-application-update-contains-a-report-or-web-part">3. How can I tell if an application update contains a report or web part?</h3>
<p>There is currently no simple way to tell if a hotfix contains a report or web part. We recommend that you assume that all cumulative updates, service packs, and feature packs contain reports and web parts, and re-deploy reports and Enterprise Portal.</p>
<p>If you encounter an error after installing a hotfix, try deploying reports and web parts.</p>
<h2 id="installation-order">Installation Order</h2>
<p>This diagram describes the order in which updates are applied in a test environment, and then applied in a production environment.</p>
<ol>
<li>Apply updates to the database.</li>
<li>Apply updates to a single local AOS instance.</li>
<li>Apply updates to a single local client. (Compile, Synchronize, and get the environment running)</li>
<li>Deploy reports to the report server.</li>
<li>Deploy web parts to the Enterprise Portal server.</li>
<li>Deploy updates to any retail components.</li>
</ol>
<p>The differences in a production environment are:</p>
<ol>
<li>Import the model store from the test environment to apply updates to the database.</li>
<li>Mass deploy client updates (optional).</li>
</ol>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/2020-01-01-microsoft-dynamics-ax-2012-update-process/Installation-Order.png" title="Image" data-thumbnail="/2020-01-01-microsoft-dynamics-ax-2012-update-process/Installation-Order.png" data-sub-html="<h2>Installation-Order</h2><p>Image</p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Installation-Order</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<h2 id="detailed-update-process">Detailed Update Process</h2>
<p>This diagram describes the update process in detail, in both the test and production environments.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/2020-01-01-microsoft-dynamics-ax-2012-update-process/Detailed-Update-Process.png" title="Image" data-thumbnail="/2020-01-01-microsoft-dynamics-ax-2012-update-process/Detailed-Update-Process.png" data-sub-html="<h2>Detailed Update Process</h2><p>Image</p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Detailed Update Process</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<h2 id="update-tips-and-tricks">Update Tips and Tricks</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p><strong>Always update in a test environment first and run the Impact Wizard for application updates</strong>
You can reduce the downtime of your production environment by fixing all code conflicts in a test environment, and identifying them early.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Make sure that you have the correct product version</strong>
Most updates apply only to released versions of a product.
<em>Note: Many demonstration virtual machines run pre-release versions of Microsoft Dynamics AX, and cannot run updates.</em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Install binary updates first, and if needed, reinitialize the model store before installing application updates</strong>
If you do not reinitialize the model store, you will encounter many more errors in the Data Upgrade Cockpit.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Do not skip the Software Update Checklist</strong>
After you install an update, on the Model store has been modified form, select Start the software update checklist.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>If you must generate CIL, restart all AOS instances</strong></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Install updates on all appropriate components (reports andweb parts)</strong>
It is difficult to tell whether an update contains modified or new reports, or web parts—we recommend that redeploy reports and web parts with all CUs.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Check to see whether all of your current hotfixes are contained in the most recent cumulative update or feature pack—if not, reinstall it</strong>
If you have a recent hotfix that is not included in the cumulative update or feature pack that you are installing, it will be removed. Reinstall the hotfix after you have applied update.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>Consider slipstreaming updates if you are doing a fresh install</strong></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>If you are installing industry solutions, install them before installing updates</strong></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><strong>To minimize downtime, consider importing the model store into a non-default schema in the production environment, and then switching it to be the default schema</strong>
For information about using non-default schemas, read How to: Create, Drop, or Reinitialize a Model Store.</p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
