<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>problem on Dynamics 365 Finance Operations &amp; Power Platform</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/categories/problem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in problem on Dynamics 365 Finance Operations &amp; Power Platform</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://nuxulu.com/47</url>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/47</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/categories/problem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AX1004 error in Dynamics AX</title>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2017-01-02-ax1004-error/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2017-01-02-ax1004-error/</guid>
      <description>AX1004 error in Dynamics AX</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Only integrated security is supported for AX queries</title>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2016-01-15-only-integrated-security-is-supported-for-ax-queries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 16:22:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2016-01-15-only-integrated-security-is-supported-for-ax-queries/</guid>
      <description>I updated my dynamics Ax development Environment by restoring Database from Production Database . After the restoring the database, when I run any report form Dynamics Ax, all gave error “Only integrated security is supported for AX queries.”
The reporting Services are still working fine.
For this, best way to redeploy them, create a new report folder, open Microsoft Dynamics Ax 2012 Management Shell (make sure you run Powershell as Administrator).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSRS Report Server Settings Validation Error- AX 2012 R3 CU9</title>
      <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2016-01-15-ssrs-report-server-settings-validation-error-ax-2012-r3-cu9/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 16:22:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/2016-01-15-ssrs-report-server-settings-validation-error-ax-2012-r3-cu9/</guid>
      <description>Recently I updated my dynamics Ax development Environment by restoring Database from Production Dynamics AX DB and I got this problem
Make sure that SQL Server Reporting Services is configured correctly. Verify the Web Service URL and Report Manager URL configuration in the SQL Reporting Services Configuration Manager.
Anyway, The reporting Services are still working fine and i have already granted the AX Admin as System Administrator under site settings, Home folder settings and DynamicsAX folder with “Browser, Content Manager, DynamicsAXBrowser, My Reports, Publisher, Report Builder” roles.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
