<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>architectural - Tag - Dynamics 365 &amp; Power Platform | NUXULU</title>
        <link>https://nuxulu.com/tags/architectural/</link>
        <description>architectural - Tag - Dynamics 365 &amp; Power Platform | NUXULU</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>luan52@outlook.com</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>luan52@outlook.com</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/tags/architectural/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Understand model store architectural in AX 2012</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/understand-model-store-architectural-in-ax-2012/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2014 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/understand-model-store-architectural-in-ax-2012/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The model store is the portion of the Microsoft Dynamics AX database where all Microsoft Dynamics AX application elements are stored, including customization. The model store replaces the AOD (application object definition) files used in previous releases of Microsoft Dynamics AX (I mean from 4.0 to 2009).
Layer and model information are integral parts of the store. The AOS has access to the model store, handles layer-flattening, and provides model data to all the Microsoft Dynamics AX sub-systems, such as form- and report-rendering and X++ code.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Architecture overview Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/posts/architecture-overview-microsoft-dynamics-ax-2012/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/posts/architecture-overview-microsoft-dynamics-ax-2012/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>Understanding the internal architecture of Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 can help you make decision when planning and developing a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 system. Here are some pointers on DAX 2012 architecture primarily for DAX 2012 architects &amp; solution developers. This topic provides a high-level overview of the system architecture of Microsoft Dynamics AX.</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="system-architecture">System architecture</h2>
<p>This diagram provides a high-level over of a Microsoft Dynamics AX 2012 system with all components installed, and describes how communications flow between the components.</p>
<p>




</p>]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
