<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Postman - Tag - Dynamics 365 &amp; Power Platform | NUXULU</title>
        <link>https://nuxulu.com/tags/postman/</link>
        <description>Postman - Tag - Dynamics 365 &amp; Power Platform | NUXULU</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/tags/postman/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>All about Odata actions in Dynamics 365 Finance And Operations</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2021-05-25-all-about-odata-actions-in-dynamics-365-finance-and-operations/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>maxnguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2021-05-25-all-about-odata-actions-in-dynamics-365-finance-and-operations/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ODATA actions in Data Entities provide a way to inject behaviors into the data model, or expose custom business logic from Dynamics 365 Finance &amp; Operations. You can add actions by adding a method to the data entity and then decorating the method with specific attributes [SysODataActionAttribute]
I use this Odata actions mostly in automation job like after refreshing data from PROD to UAT, we need to enable users, assign company to users, enable batches &hellip; Or simply consume it in Power Automate.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Testing Dynamics 365 Finance Database Movement API with Postman</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2020-08-17-testing-dynamics-365-finance-database-movement-api-with-postman/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>maxnguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2020-08-17-testing-dynamics-365-finance-database-movement-api-with-postman/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Microsoft provides a versioned set of capabilities that you can currently use to copy databases between environments, and to list and download database backups.
what you can do with Database movement API so far:
 List database backups Create database refresh Create a database export Get operation activity status  More supported actions will be added in later releases.
The endpoint uses impersonation authentication base, please follow to register a new application by using the Azure portal]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Consuming Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations OData services from .NET</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2019-12-16-consuming-dynamics-365-finance-and-operations-odata-services-from-net/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>maxnguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2019-12-16-consuming-dynamics-365-finance-and-operations-odata-services-from-net/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[1. Authentication We need an authentication to connect Dynamics 365 finance and operations from .Net application by using service principal.
How to create an app registration in Azure https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/active-directory/develop/app-registrations-training-guide-for-app-registrations-legacy-users
You also need to add required permissions for Dynamics 365 finance and operations, please follow
https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dynamics365/fin-ops-core/dev-itpro/data-entities/services-home-page#register-a-web-application-with-aad
This is what you should have
{:.border}
2. Register your external application a. In the FinOps application, go to System administration &gt; Setup &gt; Azure Active Directory applications.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Business events and HTTPs endpoint</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2019-11-05-business-events-and-https-endpoint/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>maxnguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2019-11-05-business-events-and-https-endpoint/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[In Dynamics 365 finance and operations, Business events provide a mechanism that lets external systems receive notifications from FinOps applications. In this way, the systems can perform business actions in response to business events.
There are 3 types of business events: Application business events, Workflow business events, and Alerts as business events. You can also implement a new business event.
Business events can be consumed using Microsoft Flow and Azure messaging services, and we use endpoint to manage the destinations for sending business events to, Microsoft supports many endpoints: Azure Service Bus Queue, Azure Service Bus Topic, Azure Event Grid, Azure Event Hub, HTTPS, Microsoft Flow.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Insert multiple records in single request using Odata from Postman</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2019-10-15-insert-multiple-records-in-single-request-using-odata-from-postman/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>maxnguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2019-10-15-insert-multiple-records-in-single-request-using-odata-from-postman/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Got inspired by this topic, I&rsquo;d like to write this article to show you how to post multiple records in single request by using Postman.
Generally, batch requests are supported in the OData service, The easiest way is you can use the C# code approach from github and the excel add-ins in Dynamics 365 for finance and operations use Odata batch to communicate in a single request but how can we leverage it in Postman.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
