<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Dynamics 365 Commerce - Tag - Dynamics 365 &amp; Power Platform | NUXULU</title>
        <link>https://nuxulu.com/tags/dynamics-365-commerce/</link>
        <description>Dynamics 365 Commerce - Tag - Dynamics 365 &amp; Power Platform | NUXULU</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nuxulu.com/tags/dynamics-365-commerce/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Develop custom Data Entities for Dual-write</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2021-05-02-develop-custom-data-entities-for-dual-write/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>maxnguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2021-05-02-develop-custom-data-entities-for-dual-write/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Dual-write has been around for almost two years now. It’s one of the ways of integrating Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations and Dataverse along with Virtual Entities.
The standard solution comes with many out-of-the-box entities available to synchronize. This has been one of the great improvements since Dual-write was made available in preview, when Juanan and I demoed it in the 2019 Dynamics Saturday in Madrid.
Develop custom Data Entities for Dual-write 1]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Dynamics 365 for Finance &amp; Operations and Azure DevOps</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2021-05-01-dynamics-365-for-finance-operations-and-azure-devops/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>maxnguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2021-05-01-dynamics-365-for-finance-operations-and-azure-devops/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Dynamics 365 for Finance &amp; Operations and Azure DevOps Azure DevOps Azure DevOps will be the service we will use for source control. Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations supports TFVC out of the box as its version-control system.
But Azure DevOps does not only offer a source control tool. Of course, developers will be the most benefited of using it, but from project management to the functional team and customers, everybody can be involved in using Azure DevOps.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>AUTOMATE YOUR TESTS FOR DYNAMICS 365 FINANCE AND OPERATIONS</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2021-01-01-automate-your-tests-for-dynamics-365-finance/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>maxnguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2021-01-01-automate-your-tests-for-dynamics-365-finance/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A new article for you the community. More specifically, all project managers, functional and technical consultants, as well as customer-side decision-makers on the deployment of Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations.
I told myself that it would be important to offer you a global article on all the testing capabilities (manual or automatic) for Dynamics 365 Finance and Operations. It is the result of quite a long work but which I hope will help you to improve your code delivery and upgrade processes.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Testing Dynamics 365 Finance Database Movement API with Postman</title>
    <link>https://nuxulu.com/2020-08-17-testing-dynamics-365-finance-database-movement-api-with-postman/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2020 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>maxnguyen</author>
    <guid>https://nuxulu.com/2020-08-17-testing-dynamics-365-finance-database-movement-api-with-postman/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Microsoft provides a versioned set of capabilities that you can currently use to copy databases between environments, and to list and download database backups.
what you can do with Database movement API so far:
 List database backups Create database refresh Create a database export Get operation activity status  More supported actions will be added in later releases.
The endpoint uses impersonation authentication base, please follow to register a new application by using the Azure portal]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
